Floyd S. Fierman papers, ca. 1850-1997 (bulk: 1870 - 1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series I: New Mexico’s Jewish History
  - Ravel, Arthur. (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Article on Villa's raid on Columbus.
    Article - (Woods, Clee) "Night of Fury" (March 1958).
    Documents from the U.S. Army and War Department (1916).
  - Regensberg family. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Copy of a picture of the gravestone of Jacob Regensberg.
    Information on Jacob Regensberg compiled by Al Regensberg.
    Pages from the Mora County census (1870).
    Excerpt - (Coan, C.) "Benjamin Regensberg," New Mexico History; vol. II.
  - Rivas, Tomas. (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Correspondence from F. Fierman to Rabbi Meyer (November 12, 1960).
    Notes on Tomas Rivas by F. Fierman.
    Copy of correspondence from Tomas Rivas to Martin Zielonka (August 9, 1908).
  - Rosen, Lia Lynn: Article - "A New Mexico Artist Award Puts Judaism in Apprentice's Hands" (by Cora Newmann; November, 1997). (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Rosenfeld, Robert J.: Card catalog references relating to the Rosenfeld family. (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Rosenstein, Simon. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    Simon Rothstein's bill of divorce (May 20, 1866).
    Copy of divorce settlement stating what S. Rothstein owed his wife and children (July 18, 1866).
    Miscellaneous legal documents for the divorce proceedings of Simon Rothstein (1866).
  - Rosenwald, Emanuel: Article - (Fierman, F., ed.) "Reminiscences of Emanuel Rosenwald" (April, 1962). (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Rosenwald family (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Genealogy of the Rosenwald family compiled by Lou R. Strauss, Jr.
    Genealogy of the Rosenwald family (beginning in 1773).
    Genealogy of the Rosenwald family compiled by Luscian Rosenwald (1930).
    Article - "Historical Review Carries Story of Pioneer Family" (April, 27, 1962).
    Correspondence to F. Fierman referring to information on the Rosenwald family.
    Correspondence from Robert Rosenwald to Jacob Marcus regarding Rosenwald family history (October 23, 1959).
    Correspondence from the University of New Mexico to F. Fierman which provides an inventory of the Emanuel Rosenwald papers (March 29, 1985).
    F. Fierman's manuscript for "Reminiscences of Emanuel Rosenwald."
    Paper - "Early Covered Wagon and Far West Days" (by Robert E. Rosenwald; 1982).
    F. Fierman's notes on the Rosenwald family.
    Article - "Las Vegas' Great Loss" (May 22, 1888).
    Article - "Rosenwald Bros. Building Presents Study in Contrast" (November 22, 1961).
    Copy of correspondence from Louis Sulzbacher to an unknown recipient (January 2, 1900).
    Article - "60 years of Banking."
    Copy of photograph of Nathan Jaffa in Sante Fe (August 1925).
    Copy of the program of the Chanukah festival under the auspices of the Laty Montefiore Society (Sunday, December 11, 1887).
    Copy of involuntary petition in bankruptcy for E. Rosenwald and Son (1923).
    Copy of legal documents for the case of bankruptcy for E. Rosenwald and Son (1923).
    List of dates and events which correspond to the bankruptcy case of the Rosenwalds.
    List of all claims filed in the Rosenwald bankruptcy case.
    Copy of contract between E. Rosenwald and the United States Army in the territory of New Mexico (December 15, 1868).
    Copies of legal papers in the court case of Elsberg and Amberg in Mora County.
    Copy of contract between Emanuel Rosenwald and the U.S. army which refers to the delivery of goods (May 31, 1869).
  - Rosenwald family (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 60)
    Copy of legal papers from court proceedings between Emanuel and Joseph Rosenwald and Juan Armija (March 1870).
    Copy of last will and testament of Elise Rosenwald.
    Copy of last will and testament of Emanuel Rosenwald.
    Copy of inventory of items of Albert Elsberg from Santa Fe (1862).
    Copy of announcement by E.Rosenwald and Son of their April grocery sale (in English and Spanish).
    Copies of card catalog references for Joseph Rosenwald, Albert Elsberg, Gustave Elsberg, and Emanuel Rosenwald.
    Copies of miscellaneous legal documents in regard to Emanuel Rosenwald.
    Copy of court proceedings in the case of Joseph Rosenwald and Company vs. William Kronig (1870).
    Copy of legal document which states that Lorenzo Lopez, Joseph Rosenwald, Francisco Manzanares, Juan Jose Lopez and Louis Sulzbacher agree to form the El Dorado Town Company (1867).
    Copy of legal document entitled "Submission of Trustee In Bankruptcy of Petition For Attorneys' Fees"(1928).
    Copy of court proceedings in the appeal of J. Rosenwald and Co. vs. William Kroenig (1869).
    Copy of court proceedings in the case of Joseph and Emanuel Rosenwald vs. Jacob Regensberg (1873).
    Copy of court proceedings in the case of Joseph Rosenwald vs. Andrew Calhoun (1867).
    Copy of correspondence from Louis Sulzbacher to an anonymous person addressed as 'Dear Many' (Kansas City, MO; April 9, 1890). Refers to business affairs.
    Copy of quit claim deed between Jose Martinez and Elise Rosenwald (October 1898).
    Copy of correspondence from the Missouri Trust Company to E.Rosenwald and Son acknowledging the receipt of a check for $600.00 (February 18, 1904).
    Correspondence from E. Rosenwald and Son which serves as a receipt to an anonymous party (August 17, 1907).
    Copy of quit claim deed between Joseph Rosenwald and Adolph Strauss (1884).
    'Escritura' between D. Gallegos and Emanuel Rosenwald (July 22, 1889; in Spanish).
    Copy of stock certificate for 2,000 shares of the Socorro Town Company (July 20, 1882). Signed by Emanuel Rosenwald.
    Copy of power of attorney of Juana Padilla of Las Vegas (February 10, 1888).
    Agreement between Felipe Benavidez and E.Rosenwald and Son (August 22, 1904).
  - Rosenwald family (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Roth, Henry: Article - (Groves, Bob) "The Private Diaspora of Novelist Henry Roth" (September 15, 1987). (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rothman: See: Goldenstein, R. - "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Russian-Jewish Immigrants. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Santa Fe Deeds. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    F. Fierman's notes from the Index to Deeds, Santa Fe County.
    Miscellaneous notes in regard to deeds in Santa Fe.
  - Santa Fe Jewry: Article - "First High Holy Days in New Mexico" (April 1975). (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Santa Fe (La Posada de Santa Fe). (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Postcard for La Posada (hotel).
    Article - "La Posada...A Brief History;" provides a background for La Posada beginning in 1850.
    Article - (Arnold, John) "La Posada;" Provides discussion of La Posada hotel.
    Article - (White, Mary Lee) "The Ghost;" Provides discussion of La Posada hotel.
    Article - (Arnold, John) "The Ghosts of Santa Fe;" discusses La Posada Hotel.
  - Santa Fe Old Santa Fe magazine): Article - "Old Santa Fe: A Magazine of History, Archaeology, Genealogy, and Biography;" vol. II, no. 6 (October 1914). (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Schiffer family: Correspondence from Barry Dushman to Abraham Chanin (May 26, 1993). (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Schweizer, Herman. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Article - (Ripp, B.) "Fred Harvey Man Fathered Modern Indian Arts, Crafts."
    Transcripts of obituaries for Herman Schweizer (d. 1943).
    Correspondence from the Heard Museum to Abe Chanin regarding information on Herman Schweizer (July 5, 1989).
  - Seitman, Rose: Transcription of autobiography of Rose Seitman (September 21, 1881). (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Seligman, Arthur. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Obituary for Arthur Seligman (d. 1933).
    Book excerpt: Old Santa Fe (written by R.E. Twitchell; biography of Arthur Seligman).
  - Seligman (Bernalillo Mercantile Company). (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Copy of photographs from the Cubero collection and the Lucien collection.
    Article - (Sinclair, John) "The Place Where De Vargas Died" (August 1976).
    F. Fierman's manuscript notes on the Seligman Family (includes interview with M. Seligman; biographies of Siegried Seligman, Carl Seligman, and Julius Seligman compiled by Arthur Bibo).
    Genealogy of the Seligman family beginning with Sigmund Seligman.
    Correspondence from Richard Kaufman to F. Fierman regarding corrections for Fierman's book, Guts and Ruts.
    Book excerpt - "The Place Where De Vargas Died."
    Book excerpt - selections from an unknown encyclopedia.
    Book excerpt - The Bernalillo Story (by F. Stanley).
    Book excerpt - "Viva El Pasado: A History of the Bernalillo Area."
    An index of mortgage deeds from Bernalillo County (1909 - 1936).
    Copy of court proceedings relating to the case of Ramon Lujan and Raquel Lujan vs. a list of living, defunct corporate entities, and unknown heirs of deceased persons.
    Copy of court proceedings relating to the case of Louis Felsenthal vs. W.S. Fletcher in regard to the return of muster rolls from 1861-1865 (August 16, 1890).
    Marriage certificate for Siegfried Seligman and Meta Block (July 12, 1903).
    Copy of naturalization papers and certificate of citizenship for Seigfried Seligman (September 27, 1900).
    Copy of certificate of social insurance award issued by the Federal Security Agency of the Social Security Administration to Siegfried Seligman (August 5, 1953).
    Copy of final accounting for interest in M.R. Prestridge Lumber Company Partnership (1947-48).
    Copy of statement from Jack Seligman to his customers stating that the Bernalillo Mercantile Company was sold (October 17, 1978).
    Copy of the Bernalillo Mercantile Company's director's meeting (May 26, 1924).
    Article - (Simmons, Marc) "Bernard Seligman: Jewish Merchant on the Trail" (November 1988).
    Bond issued to S. Seligman by the First National Bank of Albuquerque for $50,000 (October 28, 1915).
    Contract between Emil Bibo and the Bernalillo Mercantile Company (July 1, 1915).
    Receipts from the First National Bank to the Bernalillo Mercantile Company (1925 and 1927).
    Pages from El Agricultor Moderno (Thursday, October 14, 1915).
    Personal correspondence from Leopold Meyer to Milton (September 27, 1945).
    Copy of legal document stating that the Bernalillo Mercantile Co. and Manuel Miera are entitled to a patent for Exception No. 19 within the Pueblo of Sandia, Section Five in Township Twelve North of Range Four east of the New Mexico Meridian.
  - Seligman, Bernard. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Correspondence from Myra Ellen to F. Fierman regarding Bernard Seligman's involvement in the muster rolls in the 1890's (March 1, 1986).
    Article - "The Seligmans, Early Santa Fe Merchants" (by Marc Simmons).
  - Seligman, Carl. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Copy of court proceedings regarding the last will and testament of Carl Seligman (1971-1973).
    Pamphlet - "Trust Agreement: Seligman Bros. Trust" (November 1, 1947).
    Copy of the last will and testament of Carl Seligman (June 9, 1971).
    Contract signed by Carl Seligman stating that his two brothers are not responsible for any losses as co-partners in B.M.C. Lumber Company (August 15, 1944).
  - Seligman family (1 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Manuscript - "The Three Seligman Brothers Married the Three Block Sisters" (by F. Fierman).
    Correspondence from S. Seligman to Dr. J. Butler regarding a contract stating that Bernalillo Mercantile Co. has the right to suspend the supply of water if their own supply should fail them (August 16, 1947).
    Portion of a talk about the Seligman family by Milton Seligman (1975-6).
    E-mail from M. Amado of the Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives regarding connections between her family and the Seligmans of New Mexico.
  - Seligman family (2 of 2). (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Railroad invoices (1870, 1871).
    Copies of miscellaneous correspondence to Santa Fe from the office of the adjutant general (1899).
    Copy of correspondence from the state of New Mexico to Bernard Seligman requesting the return of muster rolls from 1861-1865 (July 24, 1890).
    Court records for the case of Louis Felsenthal vs. W.S. Fletcher (1890-1).
    Correspondence to and from Governor Arthur Seligman regarding the Democratic nomination for president (February 1932).
    Correspondence concerning the death of Governor Arthur Seligman (September 1933).
    Correspondence from A.W. Hockenhull (governor of New Mexico) to F. D. Roosevelt requesting an appeal for Otis Seligman (October 1933).
    Statement made by Melvin A. Traylor - "Why You Should Support the Democratic Victory Campaign For 1932."
    Copy of re-extension of charter of the First National Bank of Santa Fe (1870, 1910, and 1939).
    Copy of court proceedings for the case of United States of America vs. James Lopez and Arthur Seligman (March 1922).
    Copy of proceedings for the case of S. Seligman and Brothers vs. Andrew M. Adams (1865).
    F. Fierman's notes regarding the court case of Otis Seligman. Includes card catalog references.
    Copy of Fairview Cemetery interment records (1883-1932; 1932-1977).
    Copy of Fairview Cemetery interment records of single graves (1887-1940).
    Memo from G. Seligman to F. Fierman regarding an enclosed piece entitled "Mama."
    Personal correspondence taken from the Boaz W. Long Papers.
    Obituary for Ruth Seligman (date not available).
    F. Fierman's manuscript notes with regard to the Seligman family.
    Legal documents which request the return of muster rolls from the Civil War period (includes correspondence from W.S. Fletcher to B. Seligman; 1890).
    Legal document - (1876) S. Spiegleberg, S. Seligman, and L. Sulzbacher are mentioned.
    Correspondence to "Bo" from Alfred Kidder in regard to enclosed written to Madeleine from Santa Fe (November 11, 1955).
    Correspondence from the New Mexico State Records Center and Archives to F. Fierman regarding information involving Otis Seligman (July 21, 1986).
    Correspondence to Mr. Cummings from the governor in regard to Otis Seligman (October 2, 1933).
    Book excerpt - (Postal, Bernard and Lionel Koppman) A Jewish Tourist's Guide to the U.S. (Philadelphia: The Jewish Publication Society of America; 1954).
    Article - "Necrology;" provides a biography of Arthur Seligman.
    Article - "The Old Santa Fe Trading Post," El Palacio (1918).
    Court proceedings for the case of S. Seligman and Bros. vs. Jose Baca.
    Article excerpts - El Palacio (1933 and 1935).
    Announcement from A. Seligman regarding water control & Cochiti diversion dam (April 1, 1932).
  - Seligman, Julius. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Original bond for $3000 from United States Fidelity and Guaranty Co. (Baltimore, Maryland) to J. Seligman (August 22, 1932).
    Last will and testament for Julius Seligman (November 10, 1961).
    Warrant to appraisers for the estate of Julius Seligman (filed March 8, 1963).
    Court proceedings in the matter of the last will and testament of Julius Seligman (December 13, 1965).
    One page biography of Julius Seligman.
  - Seligman, Otis: Copies of Governor Hockenhull papers regarding the parole of Otis Seligman (1933). (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Seligman, Siegfried. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Legal documents written in German (August 10, 1892).
    Article - "Pioneer Couple is Honored On 60th Wedding Anniversary" (July 15, 1963).
    Copy of the last will and testament of Ed Seligman (May 25, 1965).
    Copy of the court proceedings in the matter of the last will and testament of Siegfried Seligman (May 26, 1965).
  - Sher, Sgt. Robert.: Article - (Zimmerman, Rebecca) "Jewish Soldier Says He Was Just Doing a Job" (June 1991). (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Shor, Rabbi David D. (Daniel). (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Pamphlet - "You Have Crowned Him With Glory and Honor" (Wednesday May 6, 1987). Biographical sketch of Rabbi David D. (Daniel) Shor.
    Interview with Rabbi David D. (Daniel) Shor (August 24, 1991).
  - Silber, Rabbi Mendel: Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 22, 1923). (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Sorenson, Sarah: Obituary - "Sorenson Maintained Principles All of Her Life." (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Speyer, Albert. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Copy of the inventory brought to the United States by Albert Speyer (January 20, 1845).
    Correspondence between Henry Norris and Albert Speyer regarding trade and mercantile (1845-1847).
    Copy of correspondence from the National Archives to F. Fierman regarding Albert Speyer (August 5, 1988).
    Copy of correspondence from Albert Speyer to Manuel Alvarez (May 5, 1848).
    Copy of inventory of cotton and other merchandise signed by Albert Speyer (1846-1847; in Spanish).
    Copy of correspondence from Henry Norris to Albert Speyer regarding merchandise and trade.
    Copy of correspondence to Manuel Alvarez from a list of people communicating thanks for recognizing their rights as citizens (December 8, 1840).
    Copy of photograph of Albert Speyer (1861).
    Copy of items from the Manuel Alvarez Papers relating to trade of merchandise (1850's).
    Transcription of correspondence between M. Alvarez, H. Norris, and A. Speyer (1846-1860).
    Card catalog references regarding Albert Speyer and Manuel Alvarez.
    Document from the Benjamin Read Collection discussing conflict between Mexican citizens and the United States government (1837).
    Correspondence from the New Mexico State Records Center and Archives to F. Fierman regarding a manifesto from the Alvarez Papers (September 23, 1988).
    Book excerpt - Down the Santa Fe Trail and Into Mexico: The Diary of Susan Shelby Magoffin, 1846-1847 (S.M. Drumm, ed.).
  - Spiegelberg, Elias: Manuscript - "Fatal Accident-- Death of Mr. Elias Spiegelberg." (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Speigelberg family (1 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Original manuscript - "The Spiegelberg Brothers" (by F. Fierman).
    Original manuscript - "Spiegelberg II" (by F. Fierman).
  - Speigelberg family (2 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 27)
    F. Fierman's notes pertaining to the Spiegelberg family.
    An Index to Spiegelberg family references (April 20, 1992).
    "Descendancy Chart" (includes prominent Jews in New Mexico and Arizona).
    Article from True West (April 1993). Discussion of the Speigelberg brothers.
    Article excerpt - "Entrepreneurs of the Old West" (by David Dary).
    Book excerpt - A Jewish Tourist's Guide to the United States (by Postal and Koppman).
    Article - "Solomon Spiegelberg Was First Jew in New Mexico; He Arrived in Year 1846" (April 8, 1930).
    One page of a United States census of San Miguel County, New Mexico (1900).
    A brief biography of the Spiegelberg brothers.
    Copy of document of the Parochial Pecos church record (1872; in Spanish).
    A list of the Spiegelberg references from the memorabilia in the Kriegsman's library.
    Genealogy of the Spiegelberg family beginning with Jacob and Betty Spiegelberg (July 14, 1988).
    A chronological history of the Spiegelberg family (1844-1943).
    Copy of the marriage certificate from the State of New York for Jules C. Levi and Edna Hortense Spiegelberg (December 28, 1898).
    Article - (Best, Jan) "A Jewish Heritage," The New Mexican (September 9, 1990).
    Article - (Whiting, Russ) "Landmark Tours Inspired By Heritage" (September 9, 1990).
    Article - "The Spiegelbergs and Early Trade in New Mexico" (by Hester Jones).
    Correspondence to F. Fierman in regard to information on the Spiegelberg family.
    Copy of reports on the condition of The First National Bank of Santa Fe (1883, 1892).
    Genealogy of the Spiegelberg family beginning with Jacob Spiegelberg and Betty Lilienfeld.
    Copy of indirect index to deeds for Santa Fe, New Mexico (1881-1906).
  - Speigelberg family (3 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Article - (Purdy, James H.) "The Willi Spiegelberg House" (May/June 1978).
    Magazine - El Palacio; vol. XXIX, no. 16 (November 5, 1930).
    Copy of "The Story of Navaho Sam" (by Flora Spiegelberg).
    Copy of correspondence from the State of New Mexico State Records Center to Jacob Marcus regarding information on the Navajos, Bibos, and Willi Spiegelberg (March 9, 1961).
    Copy of contract between A.H. Morehead and the Spiegelberg brothers (November 1877).
    F. Fierman's notes on the Spiegelberg family.
    Correspondence from Lehman Spiegelberg and Albert Elsberg to C.P. Clever (October, 1861).
    Copy of a selection of preliminary inventory sheets of contracts and reports from the National Archives and Records Service (Washington D.C.).
    Copy of the report on the conditions of the Second National Bank of New Mexico (June 13, 1873).
    Copy of a photograph of the Second National Bank of Sante Fe, New Mexico.
    Correspondence from the Bureau of Revenue and Library of Congress in regard to the Spiegelberg family (1962).
    Certificate stating that Willi Spiegelberg is elected to the office of Judge of Probate (November 10, 1884).
    Article - "A Prosperous Career" (October 30, 1881).
    Correspondence from Robert Levinson to F. Fierman (June 29, 1966).
    Copy of court proceedings which involves the case of Josefita Lopez de Lucero and Jose Amado Lucero vs. Willi Spiegelberg (1887).
    Correspondences from George Spiegelberg to William Parish (February 1960).
    Correspondence from William Parish to Frank Reeve (March 12, 1960).
    Manuscript - "Spiegelbergs" (by Sherri Goldstein; 1992).
    List of people who owe the Spiegelberg brothers money (May 17, 1881).
    Copy of the last will and testament of Lehman Speigelberg (1904).
    Manuscript notes relating to the Spiegelberg family of Sante Fe.
    Article - "National Bank Notes By States."
    Copy of court proceedings which accuse Adelaida Cienfuegos of pretending that her children were the product of Lehman Spiegelberg (1881; includes interrogation of Willi Spiegelberg).
    Copy of correspondence to and from the Spiegelbergs with regard to business (1856-1861).
    Copy of indirect index to deeds of Sante Fe County (1848-1934).
    Copy of correspondence from F. Fierman to Mr. Gutierrez regarding information on the case of Spiegelberg vs. Robert H. Longwell (December 20, 1962).
  - Spiegelberg, Flora. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Article - (Kramer, Anne Kulique) "Pioneers of New Mexico: Flora Spiegelberg's Reminiscences of the First Jews who Trekked Santa Fe Trail" (November 2, 1928).
    Article - "Flora Spiegelberg: First Lady of Santa Fe" (by Sharon Niederman).
    Untitled manuscript which provides history of Temple Albert as well as the Spiegelbergs, Ilfelds, Grunsfelds, and other Jewish families.
    Transcription of letter from Flora Spiegelberg.
    Article excerpt - New Mexican Magazine (February 1987).
    Chronology of lives of Flora and Willi Spiegelberg (1844-1943).
    Correspondence from William Kriegsman to F. Fierman (January 27, 1982).
    Newsletters, including an article on Willi and Flora Spiegelberg. Also an article entitled "General Sherman in Santa Fe" (by Flora Spiegelberg).
    Manuscript - "The Vigilantes of San Francisco: Heroes or VIllains?" (by Katharine E. Kriegsman; April 20, 1987).
    Copy of inventory from the Special Collections at the University of New Mexico on Flora Spiegelberg.
    Manuscript - "Flora Langermann Spiegelberg: Grand Lady of Santa Fe," (by Michael Lawson).
    Original manuscript - "Billy the Kid, the Cowboy Outlaw: An Incident Recalled by Flora Spiegelberg" (edited by F. Fierman and John O. West).
    Correspondence from Flora Spiegelberg to Paul Walter and Miss Hester Jones (1933 and 1935).
    Correspondence from Betty Hoffenberg to F. Fierman (June 29, 1988).
    Correspondence from W.E. Kriegsman to F. Fierman (May and June 1988).
    Copy of "Reminiscences of a Jewish Bride of the Santa Fe Trail" (by Flora Spiegelberg).
    Copies of miscellaneous articles about Flora Spiegelberg.
    Copy of biography of Betty Stern Hoffenberg.
    Article - "The Spiegelberg Nuptials" (1874).
    Original newsletter which includes discussion of the Spiegelbergs.